backstreetmerch.com 2019-04-15

# Backstreetmerch | Privacy Policy | Official Merch

## Privacy Policy

BSI Merch (Backstreet International Merchandise Limited) take data privacy very seriously and will always act in accordance within the law in the country of our incorporation, the United Kingdom. Our data privacy policy and procedures have been updated to comply with both the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the Data Protection Directive (DPD) April 24th 2018. 

We collect and store the following **identifiable** data when you place an order: 

Name, e mail address, telephone number, billing address, shipping address and any e mail preferences you may have chosen to grant us. 

**We do NOT store credit card numbers or any other payment information.**

We also use IP recognition to determine which country our users are visiting our store from, in order to show customers prices and shipping costs relevant to their location and to pre-complete fields in the checkout to ensure accuracy and for our customers convenience. 

We also use tracking pixels on our stores to gather **anonymous non-identifiable** data of our users online browsing behaviour. This data is used for analytics purposes (for example, but not limited to, Google Analytics) to enable us to track the performance of our stores in order to make future improvements to our customers online shopping experience. 

We may also use **anonymous non-identifiable** tracking pixels for the purpose of targeted advertising (for example, but not limited to, Facebook re-targeting advertisements) to offer our customers relevant offers, and prevent irrelevant advertisements being displayed on third party sites to our customers. 

We will only use such tracking pixels if you have expressly agreed to their use on the store. 

### Cookies

We use session cookies on our stores to allow customers to place products in their basket; these session cookies are an essential function of our online shopping cart. If you disable these cookies, you will not be able to add items to your cart and make a purchase from any of our stores. 

Most browsers automatically accept cookies; you can set your browser options so that you will not receive cookies from websites or from third party sites you can also delete existing cookies from your browser by using the options available. Many browsers can be set to suppress the full functionality of cookies which are sent from a web server to a web browser when that browser visits the server's site. 

**Would you like to accept the use of cookies and continue using the store?**

### Opt In Tick Boxes for e mail information

Our website contains "opt-in" boxes on pages where you can provide personal information (name and e mail address) for the purpose of receiving information in the form of marketing e mails. We use mailing lists, and also a sign up function for stock alerts for out of stock products. Sometimes we use a specialist third party e mail provider (including, but not limited to, Mailchimp and Newzapp) to deliver those e mails. We do not share such information with any other third parties. 

If you do not want us to send you information as described where relevant, you should leave the "opt-in" boxes unticked. 

### Other privacy information

It is possible that BSI Merch could merge or be acquired by another business. If this happens, we may share the information that relates to your order. You will be sent notice of such an event as a customer of our server and receiver of our services. 

Please note by clicking on any external links or banner advertisements will result in your transferral to another website, data privacy practices may be different to that of BSI Merch. Visitors should consult the other site's privacy policies as we are not responsible for, and have no control over, information that is submitted to or collected by these third parties. 

This privacy policy may be changed by BSI Merch at any time. The revised policy will be posted to this page so that you are always aware of our policy and under what circumstances we disclose it. 

BSI Merch will ensure that your personal information is treated with the utmost respect and in accordance with laws defined within the country of our incorporation. 

### Data Subject Access Request

If you wish to request a copy of the data we have stored in relation to your order (name, e mail address, billing address, shipping address, telephone number and any e mail preferences), please e mail your request to [customer_relations@bsimerch.com](mailto:customer_relations@bsimerch.com?subject=DATA%20SUBJECT%20ACCESS%20REQUEST). 

Please note, your request must come from the same e mail address used in relation to your order to ensure your privacy. 

We will execute such requests within one month of receipt of your e mail. 

**Please note - we do not store credit card numbers or any other payment information.**

### Right To Be Forgotten

If you wish to have all such data deleted (name, e mail address, billing address, shipping address, telephone number and any e mail preferences), please e mail your request to [customer_relations@bsimerch.com](mailto:customer_relations@bsimerch.com?subject=RIGHT%20TO%20BE%20FORGOTTEN%20REQUEST). 

Please note, your request must come from the same e mail address used in relation to your order to ensure your privacy. 

We will execute such requests within one month of receipt of your e mail. Please note – we are required by law to store this data for a period of twelve (12) months from order date to comply with financial services regulations and cannot exercise such a request until this period has passed. 

**Please note - we do not store credit card numbers or any other payment information.**

### Data Breach & Notification

In the unlikely event of any data breach, we will notify the appropriate supervisory authority without undue delay, and where feasible no later than seventy two (72) hours of the discovery of the breach. 

In the unlikely event of such a data breach being likely to result in a high risk to the rights and freedoms of individuals, we will notify those individuals without undue delay, and where feasible no later than seventy two (72) hours of the discovery of the breach. 

If you have any queries/complaints regards our data protection practises, please contact our Data Protection Officer by e mail here [Steve.lowes@bsimerch.com](mailto:Steve.lowes@bsimerch.com?subject=BSI%20MERCH%20DATA%20PROTECTION%20OFFICER%20CONTACT). We will respond to such requests within five (5) working days.
